DENNIS AWER MENSAH

Phone: +233 267048905 |E-mail: dennis.mensah.awer@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dennisawermensah/ | GitHub:https://github.com/dennisawermensah

PROFILE

A Cloud Solutions Architect with hands-on experience in using over 10 cloud products in AWS Cloud to design, build, deploy and maintain a well-architected frameworks for business needs. Dennis is client-centric and intentional about improving quality through agile-built systems in any organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Azubi Africa

Solutions Architect Trainee

Jan. 2022 - April 2022

Dec. 2021 - Jan. 2022

- Built and tested 15 projects in the AWS Cloud through the Well-Architecture Framework.
- Designed and launched to provision 5 virtual environments and databases in the cloud.

People's Pension Trust

Data Analyst

• Successfully eliminated over 20% error in data through Python.

• Added 3 more effective strategies to bring value to over 52,000 customers.

Turkish Healthcare Travel Council

May 2021 - Aug. 2021

Data Analyst

- Reduced cost of logistics by \$348.00 through data analysis in Power BI.
- Increased partnerships by 20% by implementing analysis from MS Excel dashboard.

University of Ghana Medical Centre

May 2021 - Aug. 2021

Health Service Administrator

- Increased the management of fleet by 5% through accelerated communication.
- Positively impacted over 300 patients through AIDET.

EDUCATION

University of Ghana

Sept. 2012 - March 2015

BA French, Spanish & Linguistics.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Azubi Africa Jan. 2022 - April 2022

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate.

Blossom Academy Oct. 2021 – Dec. 2021

Ghana AI Fellowship.

Virtually Testing Foundation Oct. 2021 - Dec. 2021

Penetration Testing.

SKILLS

Language: French - Fluent, English - Fluent, Spanish – Basic.

Technical: AWS VPC, EC2, IAM, ELB, EKS, S3, Ansible, Terraform, Git, Python, Linux, CI/CD, Azure. **Soft:** Strong communication skills, collaboration, team player and leader, organized, fast learner, adaptable.